What is an AEP student rubric?
AEP学生の英語能力レベル段階評価表（ルーブリック）とは？
An Academic English Preparation (AEP) student rubric
AEP学生の英語能力レベル段階評価表（ルーブリック）とは
is a scoring guide used by the teacher
能力発達評価のガイドとして、
to asses student language performance skills demonstrated in class
教師陣が学生の語学スキルの発達を評価する際に使用します。
Each student has a language rubric
学生一人一人に対して、三名の教師たちが
that all 3 teachers use to asses him or her.
この段階評価表に基づいて能力発達の評価を出します。
The language rubric is divided into seven sections.
英語能力レベル段階評価表は7つのセクションに分けられています。
There is a list of specific skills in each of the sections
各セクションに特定のスキル分野のリストがあり、
that a student must demonstrate by the end of the term.
学生は学期末までにそのスキルを取得を実証する必要があります。
Teachers checkmark a skill
教師はリストされているスキル分野を
using scores 1 through 4.
1－4で評価します。
Score 1 means that the student is struggling to understand
スコア1は、学生がスキルを理解し実証するのに
and demonstrate the skill.
苦労していることを意味します。
Score 2 means the student has some understanding
スコア2は、スキルをある程度理解しており、
of the skill and is improving stedily..
着実に改善していることを意味します。
Score 3 means that the student has satisfactory understanding of the skill
スコア3は、学生がスキルを十分に理解し、
and demonstrates competence.
能力を実証していることを意味します。
Score 4 means the student has good understanding of the skill
スコア4は、生徒がスキルをよく理解し、
and demonstrates strong ability.
強い能力を発揮いることを意味します。
The major skill areas that are assessed include:
評価される主なスキル分野は次のとおりです:
Reading comprehension; response and analysis.
読解；応答と分析
Reading strategies.
読解戦略
Use of vocabulary and sentence structure in writing.
語彙、文章校正
Writing organization.
ライティングの組織構成
Listening comprehension and thinking.
聞き取りと思考
Speaking fluency and speaking - grammar and vocabulary.
会話力の流暢性 - 文法や語彙
Teachers asses their students continually
教師は公式と非公式の評価を用いて、
giving feedback often
頻繁にフィードバックを与え
Using formal and informal evaluation,
生徒を評価します。
teachers keep notes and data to determine scoring for each student throughout the term.
そして、教師は今までの評価記録を保持し、学期を通して各生徒の採点を決定します。
The students are e-mailed their rubrics in weeks 4 or 5
生徒は4週目または5週目に自分のルーブリックをEメールで受け取り、
and are encouraged to follow their own progress
各自のスキル達成評価の過程に従い、
as they achieve and improve on each skill.
改善、進歩していくことが奨励されます。
Students will receive mid-term and final scores
学生は、3人の教師のそれぞれから、
for each skill area from each of their 3 teachers.
各スキル分野の中間および最終スコアを受け取ります。
Students much achieve an average of 3 or higher
次のAEPレベルに移行するには、
from all 3 courses in order to pass their level
3つの履修コースすべてから
and move up to the next level of AEP
平均3以上のレベルを達成する必要があります。